Yeah.
응.
So moving four were beds
앞으로 나아가면서 비트와
and cubads will be foundational computational paradise
qubit은 우리가 활용할 수 있는 근본적인 계산의 기반이 될 거야
with which we can tackle
세상의 복잡한 문제들을
complex problems in the world
다룰 수 있는
so let's try to understand the difference between them
그러니까 둘의 차이점을 이해해 보자
and where the power of cubits rise
그리고 qubit의 힘이 어디서 나오는지도
if we look at the left hand side
왼쪽을 보면
it's a way to describe and we're going to use these diagrams
이걸 표현하는 방법이 있고 이 다이어그램들을 쓸 거야
are throughout the presentation to
발표 전체에 걸쳐서
impact the power we're seen a circle
힘을 보여주기 위해 — 원 하나가 보이지
and two dots when the circle when the dot is in the north poll
그리고 점 두 개, 점이 북극에 있으면
that the zero when it's in the south pole is a one
그게 0이고 남극에 있으면 1이야
that's a classical bit to state now a cubit is the
그게 고전적인 비트의 두 가지 상태야, 이제 qubit은
unit of information in quantum world
양자 세계에서 정보의 단위야
and here we get to have with the picture
그리고 여기서 우리는 그림을 가지게 되는데
as as fear as zero no one
구 안에 0도 1도 있어
and we can have them in this superposition state
그리고 이 중첩 상태로 있을 수 있어
we have a special trick that is available to us
우리한테 쓸 수 있는 특별한 트릭이 있어
not only we can have them position in this fear
이 구 안에 위치시킬 수 있는 것뿐만 아니라
but imagine that each one of this
이것들 하나하나가
now is like a little moon
마치 작은 달처럼 생각해봐
that is in this fear and we can rotate the moon
구 안에 있는 달, 그 달을 회전시킬 수 있어
so here you're seeing that
여기서 보면
the bottom sphere has been rotated slightly
아래쪽 구가 약간 회전되어 있어
so that's why you see a little bit of blue
그래서 파란색이 조금 보이는 거야
and pink and we could rotate it all the way
그리고 분홍색도, 끝까지 회전시킬 수도 있어
so here's a hundred and eighty degree shift
여기 180도 회전한 게 있어
so we have these notion of face quantum affords us
이렇게 우리는 위상이라는 개념을 가지고 있어, 양자는 우리에게
three super powers that are exhibited in the cubans
qubit에서 나타나는 세 가지 초능력을 줘
they are the powers of super position
중첩의 힘
the power of interference
간섭의 힘
and the power of entanglement
그리고 얽힘의 힘이야
so let's impact those the principle of superposition is actually
그럼 살펴보자, 중첩의 원리는 사실
quite straight forward to understand
이해하기 꽤 쉬워
so the star on the left hand side
왼쪽 별모양을 보면
we are for north poll zero or south pole one
북극은 0, 남극은 1이야
and if we add those two states
이 두 상태를 더하면
now we have a super position cubit that has both
0과 1을 동시에 가진 중첩 qubit이 돼
zero and a one simultaneously north
동시에 0이고 1인 북극과
and softball now the right diagram is the same
남극이 있는 거야, 오른쪽 다이어그램도 같아
but now we're going to do a little trick
하지만 이제 작은 트릭을 해볼 거야
we're gonna play a gate a quantum gate
quantum gate를 적용할 거야
on what we did here is remember
여기서 한 건 기억해봐
we get to change now we get to
우린 이제 변경할 수 있어, 이제
rotate these little moons right
이 작은 달들을 회전시킬 수 있잖아
so we've rotated it a hundred
그래서 100
and eighty degrees and now we have a one
80도 회전시켰고 이제 1이 됐어
so now when we do the addition of zero plus one we end up
그러면 0 더하기 1을 하면 결국
with a super position state
중첩 상태가 돼
but notice that is different
근데 이건 다르다는 걸 봐
and the one on the left we are
왼쪽 거는 여전히
still a zero no one but now with a rotated state
0과 1이지만 이제 회전된 상태야
for the one now that is going to be very powerful
1에 대해서, 이건 굉장히 강력해질 거야
to then leverage a second really interesting thing which is
두 번째로 정말 흥미로운 걸 활용하기 위해서인데
the principle of interference
바로 간섭의 원리야
and this is not an operation that we get to perform in classical
이건 고전적인 비트 세계에서는 할 수 없는 연산이야
bid world so here in this example we have
여기 이 예시에서 우리는
a zero no one on the left plus
왼쪽에 0과 1 더하기
this new state that we created
우리가 만든 새로운 상태가 있어
which is also zero no one
그것도 역시 0과 1인데
but with this rotated moon when we do this now
이 회전된 달이 있어, 이걸 하면 이제
we get to interfere those two states
두 상태를 간섭시킬 수 있어
and notice something real interesting happened
그리고 정말 흥미로운 일이 생겼어
we've cancelled the one state
1 상태가 상쇄됐어
and we've ended up with that zero state
그래서 0 상태만 남았어
we've done that because we interfere the states
그건 우리가 상태들을 간섭시켰기 때문이야
so the next opportunity that we have right now
그러면 지금 우리한테 있는 다음 기회는
is how many states can we create
얼마나 많은 상태를 만들 수 있냐는 거야
and the beautiful thing in quantum is we get to create an exponential
양자에서 아름다운 건 지수적으로 많은
number of states so let's look at a system that has
상태를 만들 수 있다는 거야, 5개의 qubit을 가진 시스템을 보자
five cubits in this case we're depicting these cubans
이 경우에 이 qubit들을
as independent cubans right you're seeing them on the left
독립적인 qubit들로 나타내고 있어, 왼쪽에서 보이지
zeros on ones and they're getting multiplied we have five
0과 1들이 곱해지고 있어, 우리한테 5개가 있어
of them so the number of states that we can create down or
그러니까 우리가 만들 수 있는 상태의 수는
quantum computer depicted on this fear on the right
오른쪽 구에 표현된 양자 컴퓨터에서
it's too to the power of
2의 거듭제곱이야
the number of cubits we have in this case we are five
우리가 가진 qubit의 수만큼, 이 경우엔 5야
so two to the power five is thirty two states
그러니까 2의 5제곱은 32개의 상태야
so we're seeing thirty two of those little moons
그래서 저 작은 달 32개가 보이는 거야
notice that in these case we did not incorporate
이 경우엔 위상을 포함시키지 않았다는 걸 봐
any face they're all pink the powerful aspect of
전부 분홍색이야, 양자 세계에서
using this property calling tanglement in the quantum world
얽힘이라고 불리는 이 속성을 사용하는 강력한 점은
he's that we can create now states
이제 상태를 만들 수 있다는 거야
like the one depicted on the right
오른쪽에 표현된 것처럼
where we have these combinations of pink
분홍색과
and do where that's and state cannot be described
파란색의 조합이 있는데, 그 상태는
as the independent product off
독립적인 곱으로는 설명이 안 돼
these five cubits in this case
이 5개의 qubit으로는
since we have thirty two states
32개의 상태가 있으니까
with this tells us is actually something very profound
이게 말해주는 건 실제로 굉장히 심오한 거야